照
ILLUMINA…
照民
ILLUMINATIO…
照名
ILLUMINATIA…
干嘛
What?
照明电影
ILLUMINATION!
在1985年
The year was 1985,
电视上首屈一指的节目是
and the number-one show on television was…
布拉特小恶魔
Evil Bratt.
本节目由巴尔萨泽·布拉特领衔出演少年天才
The show starred young Balthazar Bratt as a child prodigy.
也是犯罪天才 决心称霸世界
and criminal mastermind… bent on world domination.
他在那 抓住他
There he is! Get him!
我可是个坏小子
I've been a bad boy!
布拉特是80年代最出名的童星
Bratt was the biggest child actor of the 1980s,
打动了全球观众的心
striking a chord with audiences all over the world.
他在那 抓住他
There he is! Get him!
但一切都在第三季结束了
But it all came to an end in season three,
因为
When…
我有没有很坏坏啊
I've been a bad boy!
这位年轻的明星经历了意想不到的青春发育期
The young star experienced an unexpected growth spurt.
节目被取消了 好莱坞将他拒之门外
The show was canceled. Hollywood rejected him.
布拉特的生活迅速直线下滑
and Bratt quickly plunged into a downward spiral.
他开始相信自己就是电视里的那个角色
Starting to actually believed he was the character he played on TV.
你看什么
What are you looking at?
让我们不禁好奇
Leading us all to wonder…
他现在在哪
Where is he now?
克莱夫
You know what, Clive?
在电视上扮演恶人很有趣
Playing a villain on TV was fun,
但现实生活中作恶会更爽
but being one in real life is even better.
盗窃音乐响起
Heist music!
来了
Here it comes.
干嘛 克莱夫
What? Clive!
你要干嘛 这怎么是盗窃音乐呢
What are you doing? How is that heist music?
抱歉 我的锅
Sorry, my bad.
妈妈呀
Mommy!
给我停
Stop right…
长官 船上混入了某个 怪物
Sir, the ship has been boarded by some kind of… monster.
等下 那不是怪物
Wait, that's not a monster.
那只是个穿了垫肩的男人
That's a man wearing shoulder pads.
只有一位超级大坏蛋的衣品会那么老气
There's only one supervillain whose fashion sense is quite that dated,
巴尔萨泽·布拉特
Balthazar Bratt.
糟糕 杜邦钻石还在那船上
Blast it! The Dupont Diamond is on that ship!
派所有附近的特工立刻出发去现场
I want every agent in the area on the scene immediately.
我们已经到了 格鲁西特工马上就到
We're already here! Agents Grucy are closing in fast.
没错 什么 你叫我们什么
Yes… wait, wha? What did you call us?
格鲁西 格鲁加露西变成格鲁西
Grucy. You know, Gru and Lucy mushed together.
你叫叫看
Try it.
我喜欢 但不太喜欢
Haha! I like it, but not a lot,
我不喜欢
I don't like it.
停下
Stop!
趴下
On the ground!
保护钻石 快行动
The jewel! Move!
快 快
Go, go, go!
不许动
Don't move!
你又来晚了 格鲁
Too late again, Gru. Ha, ha, ha…!
怎么回事
WHAAA…?
他要逃走了
He's getting away!!
他想得美
That's what he thinks.
出发
Go, go!
快行动
Ugh! Go, go.
快走啊
Go, go, go!
我们应该抓不到了 格鲁
I don't think we can make it, Gru.
我们可以的
We can make it!
可以的
We can make it…!
不行了
No, we can't!
准备好
Get ready!
准备好迎接 什么
Get ready for whaaa…!
你还好吗
Hey. How're you doing?
没事吧
Are you okay?
你们好
Hello.
你们真可爱
You guys are so cute.
去抓他 小鲁鲁
Go get him, Gru Gru!
你好啊 格鲁
Hello, Gru.
你适应得如何呀
How's your transition coming?
从世界级大恶棍变成世界最烂特工
You know, from world's worst villain to world's worst agent?
太搞笑了 你应该上电视
Oh, that's hilarious! You should be on TV!
哦对了 你之前有节目
Oh, that's right, you were…
结果节目被取消了
but then you got canceled.
怎么样
What about that?
什么 姑娘们干的
Whaaa… Oh! Girls?!
不如跳舞
Dance fight!
A队 钻石很安全
Alpha team, the diamond is secure.
快来带走它
Come and pick up the package.
收到 A队已经出发
Copy that, Alpha team on approach.
格鲁
Gru.
你真以为我失去意识了吗
Did you actually think I was unconscious?
那是我的演技 哥们
It's called acting, hoser!
显然我技艺还未生疏
And clearly I've still got it!
我可是个坏小子
I've been a baaaad boy! Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
不许动
Freeze! Don't move!
真是见了录像带的鬼了
Son of a Betamax!
快行动 抓住他 快
Go! Go! Get him! Get him!
他要跑了
He's getting away!
这事没完 听到了吗 格鲁
This isn't over, Gru! You hear me?
我跟你没完
This is not over!
那又如何 钻石在我手上
Yeah? Well, I still have the diamond!
祝你生日快乐 祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you. Happy birthday to…
祝丹生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear Daaaan.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
- 准备好了吗 - 是的
- Hey, you ready? - Yeah!
派对开始了 大家
Party! Party, everyone!
小心
Hey! Watch it!
不敢相信又一次放跑了布拉特
I can't believe Bratt got away, again.
这怎么可能 怎么
How is this possible? How…?
不仅仅是他跑了让我生气 还有他那股自以为是的劲
And it's not just that he got away! It's that he's so smug about it!
真恶心 我可是个坏小子
Ewww. I've been a baaaad boy!
你好啊 埃德娜
Edna, hey!
今天挺 美的
Looking hot… today.
身上爬了 那么多只猫
Got the… cats on you.
而且今天真羞耻
And it was just so humiliating.
穿着泡泡糖做的泳衣被吊在那
Dangling there in the bubble-gum Speedo.
我这周都没时间去健身房
And I didn't have time to go to the gym this week!
早饭还吃了好多
And I had a big breakfast!
我感觉有点水肿了
I was feeling a little bloated!
他都不值得费心讨论
You know what? He's not even worth talking about.
我都不想为他再浪费一点口舌
I don't even want to waste another breath about the guy.
还有
And another thing!
下次再见到布拉特 我要在他脸上月球漫步
Next time I see Bratt, I will moonwalk all over his stupid face!
感谢你们临时过来
Thank you all for coming in such short notice.
很遗憾通知你今天
It is with great sadness that I inform you that as of today.
我要退休不再担任反恶盟的领导
I am retiring as head of the AVL.
别啊
Oh no…
你们的新上司是从总部直接派来的 立即生效
Your new leader is coming directly from head office, effective immediately.
她就是很有天赋 野心的瓦莱丽·达芬奇小姐
She is the very gifted, very ambitious Miss Valerie Da Vinci.
扫过你们一个个的面孔 无数回忆涌上心头
As I look out over all of your faces, I am flooded with so many memories.
- 见鬼 今天真适合打瞌睡 - 我 打扰一下
- Oh boy, this is a snoozeday. - I… Excuse me.
我们明白了 你又老又肥 说完了吧
Blah blah blah. We understand. You're old, you're fat, you're done.
让我喘口气
Let me breathe in.
出了点汗
Woo. Broke a little sweat there.
新官上任三把火
First order of business.
你们哪个废柴是格鲁
Which one of you losers is Agent Gru?!
那就是在说我了
Uh? that would be me.
不过我不认为废柴这个词很恰当
Although I don't know if I'd say 'loser' per Se,
有点
kind of a… Huh!
女儿们来电话了 真不是时候
Oh, it's the girls. Not a good time.
是的 长官 女长官
Yes, sir. Huh, uh… ma'am.
你让我都紧张了
You're making me nervous.
你怎么能让巴尔萨泽·布拉特
How could you let Balthazar Bratt,
反恶盟头号恶人逃走
the AVL's most-wanted villain, just get away?
和我们的职责背道而驰啊
That is the opposite of what we do here!
没错 也许他又是逃走了
Okay, okay, yes, maybe he got away… again,
但他没拿到钻石
but he didn't get the diamond!
我差一点就能抓到他了
And I am this close to bringing him in.
就这么一点
This close!
有意思
Huh? Interesting.
你被辞退了
You're fired!
什么
Huh! What?
这太不公平了 格鲁是优秀的特工
This is totally not fair. Gru is a great agent.
你要是炒了他
You know what? If you fire him,
就得炒掉我 姐妹
you're going to have to fire me, sister sister.
真的要这么做吗
And do you really want to do that? Do ya?
不行 别这样
No, no, no, no, no.
看来她很有种
Well, I guess she did!
亲爱的 你没必要陪我的
Honey, you didn't have to do that.
我知道你多爱这份工作
I know how much you love your job.
不过我更爱别的
Well, I love other things more.
我们得把这消息告诉女儿们
You know, we're going to have to tell the girls.
你能办到吗
Can you do it?
我还没完全适应当妈这件事
The whole Mom thing is still kind of new to me.
好吧
Oh, sure.
有人吗
Hello?
- 你们好 - 你们好
- Aloha! - Aloha!
真是意想不到
This is unexpected.
你们一直都没机会去度蜜月
Well, you never got to go on a honeymoon, so?
- 我们给们你准备了了晚餐 - 是夏威夷式烤野猪宴
- We made you dinner - It's a luau!
我们有椰子菠萝还有尤克里里
We got pineapples and coconuts and lukuleles!
- 真好 - 太好了
- Oh ho, yeah. - Yeah.
女士先生 这是今日例汤
The soup of the day, madame and monsieur.
小熊糖是我的主意
The gummy bears were my idea.
太好看了都不舍得下嘴
Mmm? Looks too good to even eat!
对吧
Am I right?
但这是为你做的
But I made it for you.ah?
好汤 我真喜欢肉与小熊糖的组合
Good soup! I love the combination of gummy bears and meat!
我会含在嘴里
I'm gonna hold it in my mouth,
因为太好吃了我都不舍得吞下去
because it's so good I don't want to swallow it.
工作顺心吗
So… how was work?
你打败那个人了吗 发生爆炸了吗
Did you take that guy down? Did anything explode?
其实 今天我和露西
Well, actually, today Lucy and I…
被邀请不用再去反恶盟了
…were invited to not work at the AVL anymore.
不会吧
Huh! No!
你被开除了吗
You got fired?
不是这样的 不是
Oh no! No, no, no…
- 是的 - 什么
- Yes. - What?
但别担心
But don't worry,
我们很快就会找到工作的
I'm sure we'll get new jobs real soon.
找更好工作
Even better ones.
还有什么比当超酷的秘密特工更好的工作
What's better than being super-cool secret agents?
我知道了 我们可以在线赌博
Oh, I know! You could gamble online!
凯蒂的爸爸就干那个
That's what Katie's dad does!
我们绝对要仔细考虑一下
Okay, we will definitely look into that.
这建议不错
That's a good suggestion.
我们以后别去凯蒂家了
And let's not go over to Katie's house anymore.
（梅尔 来电）
大家 安静 你应该没听懂
Guys, sssshh! I don't think you heard me right.
不是 不是的 这不意味着我们要变回坏人
No, no, no, no, no, this does not mean that we are going back to being villains.
无聊 你以前不是这样的
Boring! You weren't like this!
好吧 我明白
Okay, alright, I get it.
听着 我知道最近并不好过
Look, I know it's been a little tough lately,
尤其是尼法里奥博士意外把自己封在了碳素里
especially with Doctor Nefario accidentally freezing himself in carbonite,
但我们的犯罪生涯结束了
But our life of crime is over!
梅尔 梅尔 你支持我 对吧
Mel. Mel, you're with me on this, right?
看看这个
Look at this!
- 很好 - 耶
- Good… - Yay!
无聊
Boring!
- 很好 - 耶
- Good… - Yay!
无聊
Boring!
- 赞 - 耶
- Good… - Yay!
无聊
Boring!!
我们不要无聊
no more boring!!
无聊 无聊
Boring! Boring!
大家 听我说 读我口型
Guys! Listen to me and read my lips!
读我口型 我们不再犯傻
Lissa me lippo, pomodoro la comquit!
什么
What? Ohh…
我说的是什么 犯傻
What did I say? "la comquit?"
好吧 我们不再犯罪
Oh, okay, pomodoro la kumquat.
你是说不再犯罪了吗
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Did you say no more crime?
我不能接受
I cannot accept this.
不许你那么和我说话
Don't take that tone with me!
我们不会再做坏人
We're not going back to villainy.
不再干坏事了？
Uh. No villainy?
没错 以后再也不要在我面前说起这件事
Yes. And I don't want to hear another word about it.
听着 我警告你们如果再不住嘴
Look, if you guys don't stop that right now,
我就给你们好看
there will be consequences!
我想做什么就做什么
I can do whatever I want.
说话注意点儿 不然你会后悔的
Don't say anything you're going to regret.
那你给我听好了 我不干了
Oh. Listen to this. I quit!
再见
See you!
什么 你要走
What? You quit?
你是认真的吗
You're serious? Come on.
兄弟们
Bud-Buddy?
戴夫 杰瑞
Dave! Jerry!
我有一个好消息 你们现在升职了
Great news, guys… you've been promoted.
你们以后就是头儿了 不错吧
You're in charge now, eh? Not bad!
好耶 好耶 好耶
Yipa! Yipo! Yippee!
万岁 万岁 万岁
Aruba-ruba-ruba-ruba!
天啊
Jeesh!
（巴黎 法国）
胖波先生
Monsieur Pompo.
请问全世界最有名的珠宝专家为什么会突然大驾光临呢
To what do we owe the presence of the world's foremost gem expert?
是警察局长派我来的
The chief of police sent me.
因为最近有人想要抢劫杜邦钻石 所以他担心
He was concerned that during the recent heist attempt,
钻石有可能已经被人偷梁换柱了
The Dupont Diamond was replaced with a phony.
哦 真不错
Ooh la la.
你们全都被骗了
You have been duped.
什么 被骗了
What? We have?
没错
Yes.
被我骗的
By me!
这是什么
Wha-What is…?
哦 救命呀
Oh no. Help!
哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha…
我可是个坏小子
I've been a bad boy!
或许我该用法语说 我可是个坏小子
Or should I say, "Je suis un mauvais garmanon!"
哦
Oh.
格鲁 你在这儿干什么呢
Hey, Gru, whatcha doing down here?
黑黑的
In the dark.
一个人
Alone.
没什么 想点儿事儿
Oh nothing, just thinking.
你没事吧
You okay?
哦 没事 对 我没事 我好着呢
Oh yes, yeah, I'm fine, I'm fine.
只是
It's just.
我不知道 我觉得我就是个失败者
I don't know. I guess I just feel like a failure.
就好像找不到人生目标了
Like I don't have a purpose anymore.
嘿 亲爱的 你才不是失败者
Hey, mister, you are not a failure.
我要是能抓住布拉特就好了
If only I could've nailed Bratt.
那么多次我差点儿就抓住他了
So many times I almost had him!
但以后再也不会有机会了
But now I'll never get the chance.
因为我已经被联盟给开除了
'Cause I have been kicked to the curb.
格鲁 你要放下这件事 你该振作起来了
Gru, you've got to let this go. It's time to look forward.
事情总会好起来的 我保证
Things will get better, I promise.
跟我走 跟我走
Follow me. Follow me.
过一过了 让路了啊
Coming through, make way.
- 过一下了 - 哦 不好意思
- Coming through. - Uh, excuse me.
打扰一下 年轻 人
Pardon me, young… people.
我想问一下到这个地方怎么走
Would you tell me how to get to this address?
你是在小黄人儿吗
You are looking for Minions?
我要找的是格鲁先生
I'm looking for a Mr. Gru.
格鲁就是个糟糕的老板
Gru is a lousy boss!
- 就是 - 就是
- Yeah! - Yeah!
再会
Bye!
笨蛋
Idiots.
不 凯尔 停下
No. Kyle. Stop!
凯尔 住嘴
Kyle, let go.
布拉特偷了世界上最大的钻石
BRATT STEALS WORLD'S BIGGEST DIAMOND.
不 不 开什么国际玩笑
No, no… you've got to be kidding me.
露西 你有没有
Lucy, did you see…
做了噩梦的话他能安慰你 而且抱着他真的感觉很好
He helps you if you have nightmares, and he's really good to snuggle with…
哦 不不 艾格尼丝 艾格尼丝
Oh no, no, no, Agnes! Agnes!
所以 请照顾好他
So, take good care of him.
谢谢你
Thank you!
艾格尼丝 你在干什么呀 你
Agnes, what are you doing? You…
你卖了你的独角兽
You sold your unicorn?
是呀 我只想帮帮你 你现在都没有工作了
Well, I just wanted to help. Since you don't have a job.
我卖了整整两美元哦
I got two whole dollars for it!
额 打扰一下
Uh, excuse me.
不好意思 我们不卖了
Sorry, buddy, the sale's over.
好的 但是我只耽误您一两
Yes, but this will only take a…
嘿 老家伙 快给我走开
Hey, Eyebrows. Get off the lawn.
好的 但是
Yeah, but…
- 嘿 能不能 - 哦 额 没问题
- Hey, could you… - Oh uh, of course.
现在 我要说了 我
Now, as I was saying. I…
- 额 哦 - 再见
- Uh… Oh. - Goodbye.
听着 艾格尼丝 你根本用不着担心
Listen, Agnes. You don't need to worry.
我们不会有事的
We're going to be fine.
- 真的吗 - 真的呀
- For real? - For real.
过来吧 我们把东西收拾一下
Now come on, let's pack this stuff up.
你不是吧 哥们 你是没弄白我的意思吧
Seriously? Buddy, you're not getting the hint.
不好意思 格鲁先生
Excuse me, Mr. Gru.
但是我真的有件事需要跟你谈一下
But I really must have a word with you.
你怎么知道我的名字
How did you know my name?
请允许我介绍一下我自己 我的名字叫弗里茨
Allow me to introduce myself… my name is Fritz!
好狗狗
Uh, good puppy.
而我今天过来见你 是因为你的孪生兄弟德鲁
And I am inquiring on behalf of your twin brother, Dru.
他需要您的帮助
He needs your help.
什么 孪生兄弟
What? Twin brother?
孪生兄弟
Twin brother?
哦对
Oh Yeah.
他希望您能乘飞机去逍遥国见他一面
He would like to fly you to Freedonia to meet him.
你们兄弟两个的父亲最近过世了
Your father has recently passed away and…
好了 疯老头 不好意思 小的时候我爸爸
Okay, cuckoo. I'm sorry, but my dad died.
就死掉了 而且我也没什么兄弟
when I was a baby, and I don't have any brother.
你肯定是找错人了
You've got the wrong guy.
是吗
Really?
那么 您又怎么解释 这个
Well, then how do you explain… this?
啊哈哈 太棒了
Ahhhhh! Bellissimo!
- 哦 你好 格鲁 - 你好 妈妈
- Oh, hello, Gru. - Hi, Mom.
现在风华正茂的时候 一定要保持足够的运动
It's important to keep active in one's golden years.
你在这里呀 我的小可爱
There you are, you cute cute.
这两个小伙子是我的潜水教练 文森佐和保罗
These are my diving instructors, Vincenzo and Paolo!
再见 帅哥
Ciao, boys!
好了 你找我有事吗
So what do you want?
妈妈 我是不是有个孪生兄弟
Mom, do I have a twin brother?
你是怎么知道的 是谁告诉的
How did you find out? Who told you?
慢着 什么 是真的
Wait, what? It's true?
你从来也没说过我还有个兄弟
You never told me I had a brother!
你还说我出生时我老爸失望透顶 所以死掉了
And you told me that Dad died of disappointment when I was born!
对 对 这是我和你爸爸的约定
Yeah, yeah, that was the agreement.
约定 你到底在说什么
Agreement? What are you talking about?
你们兄弟两个出生后还没多久 我和你爸爸就离婚了
Shortly after you and your brother were born, your father and I divorced.
我们俩说好了一个人带一个儿子抚养
We each took one son to raise on our own.
并且约定这辈子不要再见面了
And promised never to see each other again.
很显然 我只能要他选剩下的
Obviously, I got second pick.
我有一个兄弟
I have a brother.
姑娘们 坐在前排的的感觉怎么样呀
Hey girls, how are things in row B, huh?
我还特地安排了一些有趣的活动哦
I've put together some fun activities for the trip.
谁想跟我玩一把炸金花呀
Who is up for some Gin Rummy?
是吗 额 还是算了吧
Yeah. Umm… We're good.
哦 好吧
Oh. Okay.
我就坐在后面玩接龙的吧
I'll just sit here and play solitaire.
希望我能赢
I hope I win.
不知道德鲁长什么样子
I wonder what Dru will be like!
我们两个不是双胞胎吗
Maybe we'll have that twin thing.
没准我们我们会有心灵感应的 你知道吗
where we can read each other's minds, you know?
- 要是有就太酷了 - 哦 超级酷
- How cool would that be?! - Um, super cool.
逍遥国呀 逍遥国呀
Freedonia! Freedonia!
嘿 小猪 小猪
Hi, piggy, piggy!
娃 看那座房子
Whoa! Look at that house!
就像一座城堡
It's like a castle!
我等不及要见我的兄弟了
I can't wait to meet my brother!
这些猪是怎么回事儿呀
What's with all the pigs?
这个是你们的家族产业
This is the family business.
是整个逍遥国里最大规模的养猪场
The largest pig farm in the whole of Freedonia.
好吧 好猪猪
Okay, nice pig.
不 这可是我的隐私部位
No! That's my private part!
这头猪是个暴脾气
This pig has issues!
各位 请进
Please, come in.
哦 这真是太棒了
Oh, this is amazing!
就像是西斯廷教堂 但画的都是猪
Ah, it's like the Sistine Chapel. But with pigs.
我的兄弟
My brother!!
My brother!
格鲁
Gru!
德鲁
Dru!
兄弟 我要用力拥抱你
Ahhhh! Brother! I am hugging you!
我好高兴
I'm so happy!
过了这么多年 我终于见到你了
After all these years, finally I'm meeting you!
- 对 可以了 好了 - 哦 看看这一位
- Yup, alright, good. - Oh, look at that!
你一定是漂亮的妻子
You must be the beautiful wife!
你说漂亮 真是的
Beautiful, oh. Stop it!
嘴巴真甜
Sweet talker.
我兄弟怎么会找到你这种美女呢 他还顶着个秃头
How is my brother finding a wife like you when he is so bald?
你们一定是我的侄女们
These must be my nieces!
你是艾格尼丝 人很小但是眼睛大
You're Agnes, you're small with big eyes!
真想把你放进我的口袋里面
And it makes me want to put you in my pocket!
根本不可能啦 我太大了
You can't do that. I'm too big.
伊迪丝
And Edith,
我敢说你肯定是个爱捣乱的小淘气鬼
I can tell that you are a little mischievous.
我们两个待会儿一起去捣个乱吧
We're going to have to make a little trouble later.
我已经做完了
I already have!
停下 拜托 你们干什么要踢我呀
Please, stop. Why are you doing that?
（踢我）
碰个拳头 你真的很会捣乱哟
Fist bump for mischievous behavior.
还有玛格 你看着真成熟呀
And Margo! Oh, you are so mature.
我来猜一下 你十五岁了
I'm guessing what, you're fifteen?
十五岁
Fifteen?
她才十二岁 看着是十二岁 以后也一直是十二岁
She's twelve! She looks twelve. And will always be twelve.
对了 德鲁 这里真的太棒了
So, Dru? this place is amazing.
我是说一进门就让人忍不住 哇哦 哇哦 哇哦 哇哦
I mean, you just walk through the doors and you're like: wooooowwwooowwooooo!!
是不错 大概吧 是的 我不是太在意物质
Eh. It's nice, I guess, sure. I'm not really into 'things.'
娃 真是太酷了
Wow! This is so cool!
我的天啊 他甚至还有一架直升机
Oh my gosh, he's even got a helicopter!
简直帅呆了
This is the best!
没错 帅呆了
Yes, the best.
- 好了 我们现在回家吧 - 回家 为什么
- All right, let's go home now. - Home? Why?
我不知道 这个家伙 住着豪宅 开着豪车
I don't know, this guy, with the mansion and the cars.
而且还顶着像丝绸一样光滑 奢侈的长发
and all the hair, silky-smooth, luxurious hair.
我现在比来之前感觉更糟了
I feel worse than I did before I came.
但是他是你的兄弟呀 格鲁 给他一个机会
Oh, but he's your brother, Gru. Give him a chance.
我正在想 我和格鲁单独交流兄弟感情的时候
Oh, I was thinking, while Gru and I catch up on some brother stuff,
女孩儿们就都跟着弗里茨玩吧 他给你们准备了惊喜
you girls should go with Fritz. He has a surprise for you.
- 好呀 - 好呀 - 太棒了
- Yay! - Yay! - Awesome.
我最喜欢惊喜了
I love surprises!
这太好了 母女们的亲子活动时间
Oh, this is perfect. Mother, daughter bonding time.
我们快走吧
Let's do it.
再见 你们好好玩
Bye! You boys have fun.
好呀
Whoopee!
现在购买坏蛋布拉特玩具 你就能
Now you can be as evil as Balthazar Bratt.
成为他那样的坏小子
with the evil Bratt action figure,
玩偶安装着伴随音乐启动的霹雳舞模式
featuring music activated Break Dance mode.
而且配备了一对能够发射泡泡糖的垫肩
Also featuring bubble gum launching shoulder pads.
还有全新的超级钻石激光
And the all new Mega Diamond Laser.
数学滚开
No more math!
我可是个坏小子
I've been a bad boy!
超级钻石激光并不能烧掉数学书
Mega Diamond Laser does not actually incinerate books.
好莱坞怎么能停播这个节目儿呢 这些玩具多好玩啊 克里夫
How could Hollywood cancel a show that produced toys like this, Clive?
坏蛋布拉特是真正的杰作
Evil Bratt was a masterpiece.
就没有人懂得珍惜真正的艺术吗
Does no one value true art anymore?
先生 这真是一种是耻辱与嘲弄
It's a disgrace and a travesty, sir.
好了 现在我拿到钻石了 报仇的时候到了
Well, now that I've got the diamond, it's payback time.
格鲁那个家伙没跳出来阻止我 真的是太可惜了
Oh, it's too bad Gru won't be around to try and stop me.
慢着 不准说 我讨厌那个呆子
Oh, wait! No, it's not! I hate that tweeb!
至于你 好莱坞
And you, Hollywood!
这一次 该我来废掉你了
This time, I'm canceling you!
还有曾经拒绝我的失败者们
And all the losers who rejected me!
哦 猪猪 猪猪
Ooooo, piggy, piggy!
对了 你最近还顺利吗 我是说工作方面
So how are things going for you, career-wise?
啊哈哈 顺利
Ahhaaaaa, great.
特别 特别好 一级棒
So, so great. Crushing it.
我准备了一些东西 我想你会觉得很有趣的
Well, I've got something that I think you will find very interesting.
准备好 哥哥
Hold on to your face, Brother.
小香肠
Huh? Ah! Salami!
我抓到了小香肠
Hey, I got Salami.
是的是的是的
Ah, yes, yes.
是小香肠
It's Salami.
快来快来
Come on, come on.
这都是什么
What is all this?
养猪场只是真正的家族生意的幌子
The pig farm was just a cover for the real family business.
是有咪咪的格鲁
It's Gru with boobs!
请欣赏
Now, feast your eyes on.
老爸的密室
Dad's lair! Ta-da!
等等等 等一下 所以我们老爸是一个坏蛋
Whoa whoa whoa, wait. So our dad was a villain?
不不不 不是随便一个坏蛋
No, no, no. Not just a villain.
是有史以来最棒的坏蛋之一
But one of the greatest of all time!
他被称作恐怖秃子
He was known as the Bald terror.
那是他 我们的老爸
That's him? Our dad?
他非常以你为傲 你当年是个多么棒的坏蛋
He was so proud of you. And what a great villain you were.
真的吗
He was?
但对我 就不是这样了
But me, not so much.
对老爸来说 我就是个失败者
To Dad, I was just a failure.
他一直都觉得我没有成为坏蛋的潜质
He never thought I had what it took to be a villain.
但是现在 你可以帮我证明他错了
But now you can help me prove him wrong.
哥哥 教我坏蛋的艺术吧
Brother, teach me the art of villainy!
不不不不 我不能这样做
No. No, no, no. I can't do that.
什么 但这是我们的家族传统 你不能拒绝这个
What? But it's our family tradition! You can't say no to that!
听着 我很抱歉 我放下那种生活了
Look, I'm sorry. I've left that life behind me.
- 就这么简单 - 哦
- End of story. - Oh.
好吧 我理解
Okay. I understand.
我想知道这是干什么用的
I wonder what this does?
救命 救命
Help. Help!
不不不
No no no…
我的老天
Holey moley!
老爸的坏蛋专车 很棒吧
Dad's villain wheels. Pretty slick, huh?
你想开出去兜兜风吗
Hey, you want to take her out for a spin?
就玩玩
Just for some fun?
小心
Look out!
今天天气真好啊
What a beautiful day!
从零加速到四百码只要三秒 能承受核爆冲击
Zero to 400 in 3 seconds. Able to withstand a nuclear blast,
全副武装
armed to the teeth!
这挺棒的
Oh yeah. That's pretty nice.
- 还是混合动力的 - 小心
- And it's a hybrid. - LOOK OUT!
救救我
Yeah! Help me!
我可一点也不喜欢这个
I am not enjoying this…!
哇 这里在干什么
Whoa. What is going on here?
欢迎来到一年一度的逍遥乡芝士节
Welcome to the annual Freedonian Cheese Festival!
走
Go!
看 看 看这些糖果
Ooh. Look. Look. Look at all the candies.
哇
Whoa!
露西 我们能吃点这个吗
Lucy, can we get these please?
可以 但是每人只能吃一块 我认真的
Okay, but only one each. I mean it.
- 啊 - 真是的
- Awww. - Oh, man.
我开玩笑的 想吃多少吃多少
No, I don't! Get as many as you want,
- 我才不管呢 - 耶
- I don't care! - Yay!
太棒了
Awesome!
- 呃 - 怎么了
- Um. - What?
有时候也可以和她们说不 你知道吗
It's okay to tell them no sometimes, too, you know.
妈妈也需要严厉一点
Moms need to be tough.
对 对 严厉 说得好
Right. Right, tough. Good one.
我肯定能做到 我还在搞清楚当妈的这些事
I can totally do that. You know, still figuring out this mom thing.
适应新工作 老哥
Getting my sea legs, matie!
独角兽
It's a unicorn!
我们能去那里吗 求求求求求你了
Can we go in there! Please please please please please?
嗯 行啊 行
Um, sure, Yeah.
不过 咱们先 看
But first, let's, um, ooh, look!
是逍遥乡传统舞蹈 多神奇啊
It's a traditional Freedonian dance! How amazing does that look?
芝士 我爱死这个了
Chee! I love this.
那些小姑娘们从那些小伙子们那里拿芝士
The little girls go and get the cheese from the little boys.
太可爱了
That's adorable.
看那个可怜的小孩子
Oh, look at that poor little guy.
穿着那个小靴子 没人选他
With his little boots. Nobody picked him.
玛戈 你过去一下呗
Margo, why don't you go up there?
- 不可能 - 好吧
- No way! - Okay.
等等 不行
Wait a minute. No.
你去尝尝他的芝士 小姑娘
Go take a bite of his cheese, young lady.
现在
Right now.
严厉一点啊 你说的
I'm being tougher. You know, like you said.
不是 我说对她们严厉点 不是我
No. I meant be tougher on them, not me.
好啦 你就去吧 还能出多大的乱子吗
Oh, come on, just do it. What's the worst that could happen?
好吧
Fine.
你好 我叫玛戈
Hey there, I'm Margo.
你好 玛戈
Hello, Margo.
我叫尼科 你想尝尝我的芝士吗
I am Niko. Would you like some of my cheese?
太好了太好了太好了 谢谢你 玛戈 谢谢你
Yes, yes, yes! Thank you, Margo! Thank you!
我是个好妈妈
BAM! I am a great mother.
你们看到了吗 姑娘们 我放下了
Did you see that, girls? I lay down the…
不 她们在哪
Oh no. Where are they?
艾格尼丝 伊迪斯
Agnes! Edith!
你好
Hello.
看 一个独角兽的角
Uh, look! A unicorn horn!
我的小脑袋要爆炸啦
My little brain is going to explode!
呃 艾格尼丝 那是假的
Ugh, Agnes. That's a fake.
那绝对是真的
Ohhhh, it's real alright.
这个角来自扭曲森林
That horn came from the Crooked Forest.
只有这个地方独角兽还生活着
The only place on earth where unicorns still live.
笑吧 笑吧 你们
Laugh! Laugh, all of you!
他们都觉得我疯了
They all think I'm crazy.
但是我告诉你 我见过一次
But I'm telling you, I saw one once.
亲眼所见
With my own eye!
等一下等一下等一下 你见过一个真的 活的 独角兽
Wait, wait, wait. You saw a for-real, live unicorn?
它长什么样子
What did it look like?
你有没有摸摸它 它是不是闻起来像糖一样
Did you pet it? Did it smell like candy?
它是不是毛绒绒的
Was it fluffy?
它那么毛绒绒的 我都要死了
It was so fluffy I thought I was going to die.
你觉得我能不能找到一只呢
Do you think maybe I could find one, too?
据说如果一个少女的纯洁的心走进扭曲森林
They say if a maiden pure of heart goes into the Crooked Forest,
独角兽就会出来 然后永远属于她
the unicorn will come and be hers forever.
艾格尼丝
Agnes!
进球
Goal!
给我一下
Excuse me!
姑娘们 别担心 我来了
Girls! Don't worry, I'm here!
你们还好吧
Are you okay?
我们还好 你还好吧
Yeah, we're fine. Are you?
独角兽真的是真的 我要去找一只
Unicorns are really real! And I'm gonna find one!!
对不起 护崽心切了
Sorry, I went a little mama bear on you.
我听到了尖叫声
You know, I heard a scream and?
好吧 祝你开心
yeah, okay. Have a good one!
- 在这里等我 - 不要
- Wait for me here! - Don't.
停下 你踹到我了
Stop that! Ow! You kicked me.
嘿 嘿 你在干什么
Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
你偷了糖果吗
Did you just steal candies?
对
Yes!
为了两根棒棒糖下这么大功夫
That was a lot of effort for two lollipops.
不好 警察
Oh no! The police!
怎么办 怎么办
What do we do? What do we do?
上车 接下来要好玩了
Come on! This is going to be fun!
警察要抓到我们了 我好害怕
The police are going to get us! I'm freaking out!
刹车
Brakes!
警察
Cops!
哇 他们回来了
Whoa, they're back!
老兄 这太疯狂了
Man, that was crazy!
- 我们差一点就被抓到了 - 还用你说
- We're so close to getting busted. - Tell me about it.
我以为你要尿裤子了
I thought you were going to pee your pants!
- 我尿了 - 你尿了
- I did! - You did!
梅尔 累死我了
Mel, tired…
啊 梅尔 等一下
Ugh. Hey, Mel. Hold on a sec.
我们好累 好渴 好饿
We're tired, thirsty, and hungry.
- 梅尔 我好累 - 梅尔 我好饿
- Mel, tired. - Mel, hungry.
披萨 在哪 吃的 意面
It's pizza. Over there. Our food, spaghetti!
披萨 披萨 披萨
Pizza! Pizza! Pizza!
你们在干什么
Hey! What are you doing?
有人闯入 有人闯入
Intruders! Intruders!
停下 你 别动
Stop! Hey, you! Don't move!
停
Halt!
快叫支援
Call for backup!
跟上 跟上 快走 快走
Come on. Come on. Let's go, keep going.
这是什么
What's this?
（达人秀）
高兴了吧 都怪你 做些什么啊
Happy? It's on you. Do something!
不要 不要 不要 不要 不要 不要
No, no, no. No, no, no.
抓住他们 快 快
Get 'em! Go! Go!
你 别动
Hey, you! Freeze!
别动
Don't move!
手举起来
Hands in the air!
面对现实吧 格鲁 当坏蛋的本性就在你的血液里
Face it, Gru. Villainy is in your blood.
你不可能告诉我你不怀念这种快感 一点都没有
You can't tell me you don't miss the rush. A little?
嗯 也许有一点吧
Well… Yeah, maybe a little.
现在你有了一个回到巅峰的机会
And now you've got a chance to get back on top.
找回你的魔力 重新做回格鲁
Get your mojo back. Become Gru again!
这要有多棒啊
How awesome would that be?
求求你了 来吧 就偷一次
Oh please, come on, just one heist.
世界上肯定有某个东西 在某个地方
There's got to be something out there, somewhere,
你还想偷走的
that you still want to steal.
嗯 倒是有个东西
Hmmmm… There is something.
我们去把世界上最大的钻石偷走怎么样
How about we steal the largest diamond in the world?
好 我喜欢
Yes! I love it!
谢谢你 哥哥
Oh, thank you, Brother!
我发自内心地谢谢你
Thank you from the bottom of my heart!
我们应该庆祝一下
Oh! You know what? We should do something to celebrate.
我有一个完美的主意
Ohhhh. I've got the perfect idea.
弗里茨 好同志
Fritz, my good fellow.
你能再给我拿一块餐巾吗
Could you get me another napkin, please?
好的 当然 伊迪斯小姐
Oh yes, of course, Miss Edith.
格鲁和德鲁去哪了
Hey, where are Gru and Dru?
我们在这里
Here we are!
你们好吗
How's it going?
是我 格鲁
It's me, Gru.
我 德鲁
And me, Dru.
我和所有人拥抱 不管他们喜不喜欢
I hug everybody whether they like it or not.
他们为什么要假装是对方
Why are they pretending to be each other?
晚饭吃什么 我估计不会喜欢
What's for dinner? I probably won't like it.
毕竟我一直都这么暴躁
I'm so grumpy all the time!
我笑个不停
Hey! I laugh a lot!
我有点傻
And I'm kind of an idiot!
我肚子好疼
Oh, a bust in the gut.
看她们 完全看不出来
Look at them! They had no idea!
完全骗到了
Total burn.
看 是我 格鲁
Oh, look, it's me…Gru!
我是德鲁 我们互换了
And I'm Dru! We switched places!
看你们两个相处得这么好真棒
Awww. It's so nice to see you two are getting along.
- 我们相处得 - 太好了
- Oh, we're getting… - Along perfectly.
- 等等 我们是不是 - 接了
- Wait. Did we… - Just finish…
- 对 - 方的
- Each… - Other's…
- 话 - 话
- Sentences? - Sentences?
这真棒 一点也不诡异
Aw, that's delightful. Not creepy at all.
不过你们要停下来了 是吧
And you're gonna stop now, though, right?
抱歉 双胞胎之间的事
Sorry, it's a twin thing.
行吧
Uh-huh.
所以你们两个今天干什么了
So… what did you guys do today?
- 没什么 - 没什么
- Nothing! - Nothing!
好吧 是什么
Okay. What is it…
吃完了
All done!
闪开 晚安各位
Out of the way! Good night, everybody!
等等等等 停一下 你急什么
Hey, hey, hey, put the brakes on. What's the rush?
我要去睡觉了这样我能起来去找独角兽
I need to go to bed so I can wake up and find a unicorn!
晚安
Good night!
这是怎么回事
What was that about?
艾格尼丝觉得她明天会在树林里找到一只真的独角兽
Agnes thinks she's going to find a real unicorn in the woods tomorrow.
她都要抓狂了
She's totally freaking out.
我觉得有人要去告诉她真相
I feel like someone got's to tell her the truth.
我不去
Not it!
别担心
Ohhh, don't worry.
这是育儿的基础知识 我来
Parenting 101. I've got this.
请保佑当我找到独角兽的时候
Ummm… And please bless that when I find the unicorn,
他会和我一起回家 睡在我的房间
he'll want to come home with me. And sleep in my room.
我可以每天骑他上学
And that I can ride him to school every day.
他会用他的魔法帮我做数学题
And he will use his magical powers to help me do math.
阿门
Amen.
你好 格鲁
Oh. Hi, Gru.
你好 明天是个大日子啊
Hey. So big day tomorrow.
对啊 我终于能看到独角兽了
Yeah, I'm finally going to get to see a unicorn!
真的
For reals.
如果我找到了 我能带它回家吗 求求你了
If I do, can I bring it home, please?
哦 好啊
Ohhh. Yeah, sure.
告诉你 你找到的独角兽
Tell you what, every unicorn you find,
都可以带回家
you can bring it home.
我最好建高大的围栏 对吧
I'd better build a big pen, right?
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
有可能你就是找不到
there's a chance that you might not find one.
我
I'm…
也许现在不是独角兽活动的季节
It might not be good unicorn finding weather.
它们不好找
They're tricky to find them.
我也不清楚
And I don't know.
也许 只是 也许独角兽并不真的
Maybe, just… maybe unicorns don't really ex…
会在森林那面活动
…explore that part of the woods.
但那个人说
But the man said.
心灵纯净的少女能够找到
a maiden could find one if she was pure of heart.
我心灵很纯净吧
And I'm pure of heart, right?
最纯净的
The purest.
我们能不聊了吗 我想睡觉
Can we stop talking now? I need to get to sleep.
晚安 亲爱的
Goodnight, sweetie.
晚安 格鲁
Goodnight, Gru.
我爱独角兽 我爱独角兽
Unicorns I love them. Unicorns I love them.
我没事
I'm okay.
（州立监狱）
还给我
Hey! Give that back!
别这样
Huh? Come on!
大伙 别离开我
Guys! Don't leave me!
不要 快跑
Oh, no! Run!
我们等很久了
We've been waiting a long time.
不要啊
No. No. Ow!
求你了 别这样
No. Please, don't.
格鲁
Gru?
我的飞机 坏了
My plane… broken.
伙计们 我决定了
Buddies, I've decided.
我们要回去找格鲁 我们要回去找锅炉
We're going back to Gru. We're going back to Gru!
因为我为了那个大日子一直在训练
Because I'm training for the big day,
没人能阻拦我
nobody's gonna stop me.
因为我脸皮超级厚 超级厚 超级厚
'cause I am super sassy. Super sassy. Super sassy.
今天什么计划 老大
What's today's plan, boss?
什么计划
What's the plan?
傻机器人 我让你看看是什么计划
Silly robot. I'll show you the plan.
是时候观看一集非常特别的布拉特小坏蛋了
Time to watch a very special episode of Evil Bratt.
看看我到底要如何对付那个浮夸的傻瓜
to see exactly what I'm going to do to stupid Tinseltown.
本周的布拉特小坏蛋
This week on "Evil Bratt".
布拉特小坏蛋机器巨人来了 开火
It's a giant Evil Bratt robot! Open fire!
想得美 条子们 给你们嚼嚼
Nice try, coppers. Chew on this!
他发射了独门的超黏自发泡泡糖
He's shooting his super sticky self inflating gum!
快跑
Run!
我为泡泡 泡泡为我
Gum one! Gum all!
Gum one. Gum all.
说真的 这节目怎么没得艾美奖
Seriously, how did this show never win an Emmy?
现在 我的钻石 是你发挥威力的时候了
And now, it's your turn to shine, my diamond!
克里夫
Hey, Clive.
你可以说我们的计划是 打败世界
I guess you can say our plan was… out of this world.
娱乐时间结束了
Now that's entertainment.
走 我们去把它变成现实
Come on. Let's make it a reality.
我们来了 在黑暗扭曲古怪的森林
Here we are, in the dark and creepy Crooked Forest,
寻找神秘的独角兽
in search of the mythical unicorn.
为了某种原因
For some reason.
她来了 无畏的独角兽猎手 寻找
And here she is, the fearless unicorn hunter, seeking the…
伊迪丝 别闹
Edith, stop it!
你会吓跑独角兽的
You're gonna scare away the unicorn!
要是我们刚好找到了独角兽
If somehow we actually find a unicorn,
我要把它录下来靠它赚钱
I'm gonna film it and get rich.
看那边
Look over there!
就是这里了 我们会在这里发现它
This is it! This is where we're gonna see it!
独角兽 我们来了
Unicorns, here we come.
那是什么
What's that for?
诱饵 没见识了吧
Bait. Duh.
跟我来
Come on!
现在我们只需要等了
Now all we have to do is wait.
你好 这里是布拉特的巢穴
Okay. This is Bratt's lair.
也许看起来不怎么样 但这里装备了
It may not look like much, but this place is armed.
人类史上最厉害的高科技武器
with some of the most high-tech weaponry known to man.
是刀枪不入的
It's considered impenetrable.
但对我们来说是小菜一碟 对吧 哥哥
But a piece of cake for us, right, Brother?
这和偷棒棒糖可不一样
This is not like stealing lollipops.
这个安全系统能侦查任何方向来的空袭
This security system can detect an air assault from any direction.
不要啊
No! Ouch!
救命
求你了 停手
Please! Stop! Ouch!
我们只能在下面通过 在水边行动
So we'll have to approach low and close to the water.
接下来
Next.
还有这些致命的长钉
Then there are these deadly spikes.
杰罗尼莫
Ha ha ha ha! Geronimo!
上面涂的毒药足以让你震惊 真的
Covered with enough poison to blow your mind… literally.
好痛
Ouch! Ha ha ha ha ha!
这不可不知
Ah… Good to know.
计划是这样
So here's the plan.
你当逃跑时开车的
You're the getaway driver.
所以你在船上等着
So you'll wait in the boat.
等下 在船上等着
Wait, hold on. Wait in the boat?
但 我想参与行动
But… I want to be in on the actions!
逃跑司机是任何行动中最重要的部分
The getaway driver is the most crucial part of any plan.
你知道坐着什么都不做 什么都不碰
Do you know how hard it is doing nothing, touching nothing,
肾上腺素却充满了你的静脉有多难
with all of the adrenaline coursing through your veins.
那你也必须等待
and you must wait.
我能指望你吗
Can I count on you?
应该吧
I guess so?
然后 我会爬上魔方 从这里进入
So… I'll climb up the cube and enter here.
我进去后 会找到钻石
Then once I'm inside, I'll find the diamond.
我曾小看过布拉特 这不会那么简单
I've underestimated Bratt before. It's not going to be easy.
我们应该能对付
I think we can handle it.
爸爸的坏蛋服 这会让我们所向披靡
Dad's villain suits! This will make us unstoppable.
真帅啊
Whoa. Ay, chihuahua!
我要黑的
I call the black one!
该出发了
It's go time!
你好
Hello. Oh, hi.
你好 玛格的母亲 我是尼科
Hello, mother of Margo. I am Niko.
我将这只猪献给你代表我对与您女儿订婚的诚意
I present you with pig to confirm my engagement to your daughter.
- 怎么回事 - 发生了什么
- Hey, what now? - What's going on?
还记得 小靴子吗
Remember, little boots?
你好 我的爱人
Hello, my schmoopsie poo.
他似乎觉得你们订婚了
He seems to think you're engaged.
什么 我们才没订婚
What? We're not engaged!
听着 尼科 你似乎是个好人
Look, Niko. You seem like a very nice boy.
小猪也很可爱
With a very nice pig.
但是你们没订婚
Uh, but you're not engaged.
不可能的
Okay? It's not happening.
我理解 我在骗谁
I understand. Who was I kidding?
我这样的牛粪怎么配得上你这样的女神
A dumpling like me with a goddess like you?
但我向你保证 我绝不会忘记你 玛格
But I promise: I will never forget you, Margo.
绝不
Never.
恐怕我也不会忘记你了
Oh, I'm pretty sure I won't forget you, either.
再见 尼科
Bye. Bye, Niko.
刚才太出乎意料了
Wow, that was crazy! Wooo!
真丢人
That was totally humiliating!
非要咬一口那奶酪是我做过最愚蠢的事了
Taking a bite of that cheese was the stupidest thing I've ever done.
我当时为什么听了你的
Why did I listen to you?
没错 但都结束了 所以
Right, but it's over now, so…
又来了 尼科
Ugh, here we go. Niko…
你 你拒绝了我儿子的订婚猪吗
You! You refuse my son's engagement pig?
什么
What?
祝你和你女儿痛苦地慢慢死去 和洋葱埋在一起
May you and your daughter die a slow death and be buried with onions!
行了 女士 够了
Alright, lady. That's it!
没人 没人 能骂我的女儿 明白吗
Nobody… nobody! …curses my daughter! You got that?
因为你敢惹玛格 就是惹我
Because if you mess with Margo, you mess with me!
我向你保证 你绝不想惹我
And I promise, you do not want to mess with me!
听明白了吗
Do you understand me?
明白了
Yes, yes.
很好 滚吧
Good. Now, GET!
听着 玛格 我们只需要
Look, Margo. I think we just need to… Oh.
太好了
Yes!
我得告诉格鲁
Oh! I've to tell Gru!
- 我们能回去了吗 - 这么快
- Can we go back now? - Already?
再坚持几小时
Just a couple more hours!
我们得在天黑前回家
We have to be home before it gets dark.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我完全照着那个人说的做了
I did exactly what the man said.
你是说那个被所有人嘲笑的人独眼刀疤仔吗
You mean that one-eyed, scar-faced man that everybody laughed at?
是啊 不可能啊
Yeah. It makes no sense.
听着 艾格妮丝 也许我们没有
Look, Agnes, maybe we're not…
我的一生都在等这一时刻
My whole life has been building to this moment!
是一头
Um. It's a…
独角兽
Unicorn!
不敢相信
I can't believe it!
我要叫你小吉祥
I'm gonna name you Lucky!
小吉祥 别舔了
Oh, Lucky, stop it…
好吧 还是让别人打破她的梦吧
Yeah. I'll let someone else burst her bubble.
看看我们 雄雄双煞
Look at us! Two brothers pulling a heist.
那颗钻石会让我们成为最富有的人 世界最厉害的恶人
And that diamond will make us the richest, most powerful villains in the world!
对吧 哥
Right, Brother?
是的 没错
Right. Yeah. Yeah…
太好了 好极了 你真棒
Bravo! Bravissimo! You're amazing!
我真抱歉 真不好意思 我之前很无理
I'm so sorry. I'm so embarrassed. I was very rude.
- 你一直大人不记小人过 - 你成功了 你成功了
- And you were always such a gentleman. - You did it! You did it!
你找回了我们的工作
You got our jobs back.
什么 当然 很好
What? Oh yeah. Right. Sure.
看啊 我们到了
Oh look, we're here!
我要进去了 拿好方向盘
I'm going in. Take the wheel.
我还是不明白为什么不能和你一起去
I still don't see why I can't go with you.
我们讨论过了
Hey. Hey, we discussed this.
现在不是破坏计划的时候
Now is not the time to mess with the plan.
好吧
Fine…
- 哥 - 怎么了
- Hey, brother. - What?
我说了 你应该待在船上的
I told you, you were supposed to stay with the boat!
我没想到真的是字面的意思
Oh, I didn't think you meant that literally.
不然我是啥意思呢
What other way could I have meant it?
好吧 听我指挥 跟我走
Alright. Let's move. Just follow my lead.
收到
Got it.
救救我
Help me! Ow! Ow! Ow!
该死 毒刺
Oh no! The poison spikes!
我要被刺穿了
Oh, I'm gonna be impaled!
我没事
Ha ha! I'm okay!
我想小黄人了
I miss the Minions.
快跟上
Come on!
来了
Coming.
快点
Come on!
这有扫描仪
It's a scanning device!
快转变 伪装模式
Quick… camouflage mode!
别动 闭眼
Freeze! And close your eyes.
捂上嘴
And cover your mouth!
好了 抓住我的手
Okay. Take my hand!
跟我走
Ha ha. Follow me!
小心
Look out!
你是对的 我应该留在船上
You're right. I should've stay in the boat.
我有点反胃
My stomach feels all queasy.
不该吃那个热馅饼的
I shouldn't have eaten that hot pie.
别紧张
Hey. Hey. Relax.
你会没事的 我保护你
You're going to be just fine. I got your back.
跟我来 这边走
Come on, this way.
格鲁会拿这个 格鲁会拿那个
Gru would take this. Gru would take that.
快行动
Go, go, go!
彼得 这边
Eh. Peter, that way.
好
Oh, okay, okay.
走吧 快
Go, go. Go, go, go!
快回来
Huh? Hey, come back.
你好 你好 你好
Hello. Hello. Hello.
救生外套就在你们身边
You jacket is located within easy reach.
拉开栓扣为救生衣充气 像这样
Inflate your jacket by pulling the toggle. Like this…
感谢你们的关注 祝您旅途愉快
Thank for your attention, enjoy your flight.
直走 直走 直走
Straight ahead. Straight ahead. Straight ahead.
伙计们 等等我
Bud-Buddy. Bud-Buddy!
等等我啊
Buddyyyy!!!
似乎就在我们头顶上方
It looks like it's right above us.
我该怎么办 应该在通风孔等着吗
Okay! What do I do? Should I wait in the vent?
不 跟我走
No. Come with me.
我想感谢奥斯卡评委会
Yes, I'd like to thank the Academy.
- 我能拿 - 不行 别上手
- I can… - No no no no no…
- 为什么 我可以的 - 别 别冲动
- Why? I can do it. - Don't, don't, don't!
好的 莫莉·林沃德 我会带你参加学校舞会
Yes, yes, Molly Ringwald. I will take you to the prom.
怎么回事
Where… What…
谁在那 谁在那
Who's there? Who's there?
99个红气球
Ninety nine red balloons…
哎呦 差点忘了
Whoops! Almost forgot.
过来
Shhh, shhh. Over here!
跟紧
Stay close!
娃娃
Dolls.
看来蠢到买这玩意的只有布拉特本人了
Looks like Bratt was the only one stupid enough to buy this junk.
我以前也有一个
Oh. I used to have one of these!
快跟上
Hey! Shh! Come on!
我们越来越近了
Alright. We're getting close.
从现在开始 每一步必须极其小心有目的性
From now on, every move must be made with ultra precision and purpose.
泡泡糖
Gum!
集中精力
Focus!
入侵者 入侵者 入侵者
Intruders! Intruders! Intruders!
别动 两个笨蛋
Freeze, dipsticks!
格鲁 你怎么有两个
Gru! There's two of you now?
看来能有双倍的乐子了
Then this will be twice as much fun.
把我的钻石还回来
Aaaaah! Give me back my diamond!
全面封锁
Total lockdown!!
小的们 抓住他们
Go get 'em, Bratt Pack!!
他们要抓到我们了 他们要抓到我们了
They're gonna get us! They're gonna get us!
快跑
Run!
我们要死了吗 我们要死了吗
ARE WE GONNA DIE?? ARE WE GONNA DIE??
我们要死了
WE'RE GONNA DIE!!
什么
What?
伙计们 撑住了
Hey, guys. Hold on!
露西
Lucy!
谢谢你救了我们
Thank you for saving us! Woo!
看 我们拿到钻石了 我们要
Look! We got the diamond! And we're going to…
带着他回到联盟 找回工作
Take it to the AVL and get our jobs back!
等等
Wait!
什么 那太好了
What? That's amazing!
最妙的是 你再也不用
And the best part is you are never ever.
背着我偷偷行动了
go behind my back ever again!
- 懂了吧 亲爱的 - 懂了 懂了
- Right, honeybear? - Yup! Yup! Right.
得到教训了
Lesson learned.
我去叫女儿们 然后打包行李宣布这个好消息
I'll get the girls and start packing and tell them the good news!
我们能找回工作了 耶
Ah, we're getting our jobs back, yeah!
对 对 去告诉女儿们
Yes. Yes. Go tell the girls.
不 没门 我们不能把钻石还回去
No. No way! We can't give the diamond back!
- 我必须这么做 - 你不用
- I have to. - No, you don't!
- 我必须还 - 把它给我
- Yes, I do. - Give it.
- 不行 - 给我
- No! - Give it!
嗷 你是不是有毛病
Ow! What is wrong with you?
你是不是有毛病
What is wrong with you?
你踢了我
You kicked me!
你 你骗了我
You-You lied to me.
我本想告诉你真相
Hey. I would have told you the truth.
但你就是个胆小鬼 根本接受不了
But you're too much of a wimp to handle it.
就这样 我走了
That's it, I'm out of here.
你没权利拿走 我们俩一起偷的
You have no right to take that, we stole it together.
一起
Together?
你一定是在逗我
You got to be kidding me.
你除了惹麻烦什么也没做
You did nothing but screwed up the whole time.
就这样我还拿到了
I got this in spite of you.
哦 是吗 至少我不会像失败者一样
Oh, yeah? Well, at least I didn't get fired.
被老板开除丢掉工作
from my job like a total loser.
至少我还有工作
At least I had a job.
而你又做了什么值得骄傲的事
What have you accomplished that was so great?
让我来告诉你 没有
I'll tell you what: Nothing!
难怪老爹会认为你是个失败者
No wonder Dad thought you were such a failure.
我们再也不是兄弟了
We're no longer brothers!
我求之不得
That's fine with me!
格鲁 我找到独角兽啦
Gru! I found a unicorn!
我的人生完美了
My life is complete!
宝贝 那 那其实不是真的独角兽
Honey, that's… that's not actually a unicorn.
但是他有个角
But-But he has one horn.
抱歉 宝贝 但是
I'm-I'm sorry, sweetie, but…
他就是只山羊
he's just a goat.
有时候人生就是如此
Life is just like that sometimes.
我们期待的是独角兽
We're hoping for a unicorn.
得到的却是山羊
and we get a goat.
好吧 你知道么
Well, you know what?
小吉祥是世界上最可爱的山羊
Lucky is the best goat in the whole wide world!
看看他的脸 我真的好想抱紧他
Look at that face! I just want to squeeze it.
我来拿这个
I'll take this.
你可真是个坏小子 格鲁
You've been a bad boy, Gru.
把剩下的箱子拿过来好吗
Can you get the rest of the suitcases?
走了 姑娘们 我们走
Come on, girls, let's go!
让我们动起来 动起来
Let's get physical, physical!
计划有变 姑娘们
Change of plan, girls.
我们暂时不回家
Instead of going home…
眉毛 哎呀
Eyebrows. Ow!
我们去好莱坞
We're going to Hollywood!
看到没 这就是演技
Now that's what I call acting.
走吧 克里夫 大机器人还等着我们呢
Let's go, Clive. We've got a giant robot waiting.
露西
Lucy?
布拉特 他劫走了女儿们
Bratt, he took the girls!
什么 不
What? No!
德鲁 德鲁
Dru! Dru!
走开 我不想和你说话
Go away. I don't want to talk to you.
布拉特劫持了姑娘们
Bratt has the girls!
听着 兄弟 之前
Listen, brother. What…
- 我说的那些 - 不 是我先
- About what I said. - No, I'm the one…
但我不该那么说
But I shouldn't have…
我 我对不起
I'm-I'm sorry.
我也是 格鲁
I'm so sorry, Gru.
当心
Oh, look out!
那是什么
What is that?
嘿 嘿 前面
Hey. Hey! In front of!
妈呀 妈呀
Caramba! Caramba!
妈呀
CARAMBAAAAA!
梅尔
Mel?
格鲁
Gru?
快给这玩意儿掉头
Got to turn this thing around…
格鲁
Gru!
等等 格鲁
Wait up! GRUUUUU…
你好 好莱坞
Hello, Hollywood!
我回来了 而且更大了
I'm back and bigger than ever.
我好害怕
I'm scared!
谢谢 谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you so…
别把我丢在这 我是大腕啊
You can't leave me here! I'm famous!
克里夫 装备加农炮
Clive, arm the cannons.
尝尝这个
Chew on this!
大胡子 放我们出去
Hey, mullet-head. Let us out!
别担心 姑娘们
Oh, don't worry, girls.
我给你们准备了前排的座位
I've prepared a front row seat for you.
艾格尼丝
Agnes!
又一次 我胜利了 格鲁输了
Once again, I win and Gru loses.
好好欣赏吧 姑娘们
Enjoy the show, girls.
什么鬼东西
What in the heck?
但愿孩子们都安全
I hope the girls are okay.
布拉特 兄弟
Bratt! Brother!
在9点钟方向 不 3点钟
9 o'clock. No. 3 o'clock.
他就在左边
He's on the left!
不 我以前看过这一幕
Huh, no. I've seen this episode.
他要用泡泡糖裹住整座城市
He's going to bubble gum the whole city.
然后送进太空
and send it up into space.
快点
Hurry!
就是这样 就是这样
This is it. This is it.
灯光 相机
Lights! Camera!
激光
LASER!
（大世界唱片）
看 我去救她们
Look. I got the girls.
你们俩去对付布拉特
You two go take care of Bratt.
等等 你要做什么
Wait. What are you doing?
大家快看 是露西
Look, you guys. It's Lucy.
露西 这里 救命
Lucy, over here. Help! Help us!
妈妈来了 姑娘们
Mama's coming, girls.
- 露西 - 这里 露西
- Lucy! - Right here! Lucy!
瞧瞧那激光
Look at that laser go.
我就喜欢计划成功的感觉
I love it when a plan comes together.
是格鲁
Aaaah! It's Gru!
准备好 布拉特
Get ready, Bratt.
我要把你打回80年代
You're about to be blasted back to the 80s.
我们打败他了
Ah ho! We got him!
- 糟了 - 别担心
- Oh no. - Don't worry.
我们的弹药多着呢
There's more where that came from.
想阻止我可没那么容易
It'll take more than that to stop me.
小子们 去抓住那个死秃头
Bratt pack, go get that barf bag.
过来了
Oh, incoming!
你这个小
You, little…
快 跳
Quick! Jump!
太棒了
Boners!
看到了没 克里夫 都完了
Did you see that, Clive? All gone.
再见 神奇双胞胎
Bye bye, Wonder Twins.
看那些巨型气泡
Look are all those giant bubbles!
救命
Help!
抓紧
Hang on!
撑住 姑娘们 我来救你们
Hang on, girls! I got you!
撑不住了 我在往下滑
I can't. I'm slipping!
不
No!
抓住了
Gotcha.
谢谢你 露西
Thank you, Lucy.
我们走 我们还没安全呢
Let's go! We're not safe yet!
小黄人们 是时候做你们最擅长的了
Minions, time to do what we do best.
我们为老大欢呼 我们为老大而战
We will cheer for our boss. We will fight for our boss.
我们来戳破这些泡泡
We'll pop the bubbles!
- 坏蛋 - 坏蛋
- Villain! - Villain!
你们也是 你们也是坏蛋
You guys too! You guys are villains!
看看这是谁
Look at what we have here.
抱歉 格鲁 我要把你烤焦了
Sorry, Gru. This is going to be a total burn.
哦 不 不不不不不
Oh, no. No! No, no, no, no…
我可是个坏小子
I've been a bad boy!
谁都别想动我兄弟
Nobody messes with my brother!
什么 怎么回事
What? What's happening?
德鲁
Dru!
坚持住 我来了
Hold on! I'm coming!
你毁了一切
You've ruined everything.
现在 去死吧
And now, it's time to die.
有什么遗言吗 格鲁
Any last words, Gru?
知道吗
You know what?
我就送你两个字
I got two words for you.
斗舞
Dance fight.
没问题 大金刚
Oh, it is alright, Donkey Kong.
我一定会好好享受的
I'm going to enjoy this.
够了
Enough!
轮到我了
My turn.
游戏结束
Game over!
你在找这个吗
Is this what you're looking for?
不
No!
No…!
诅咒你 格鲁
Curse you, Gru!
诅咒你
Curse you…
比尔 过来 罗伯特 做好你的工作
Bill, over there! Robert, work your pick.
查克 再用力点
Chuck, more bashing!
德鲁
Dru.
我们成功了
Hey, we did it!
是的 我们成功了 兄弟
Yes, we did, brother.
- 格鲁 - 格鲁
- Gru! - Gru!
姑娘们
Girls!
格鲁
Gru!
梅尔 欢迎回来
Hey, Mel. Welcome back.
爱你 妈妈
Love you, Mom.
我是妈妈啦 我是妈妈啦
I'm a Mom. I'm a Mom!
打他
Hit it! Ha ha!
骗子
Cheater!
- 这个怎样 骗子 - 不 不
- How do you like this, Cheater? - No. No.
伙计们 睡觉时间到了
Boys. Time for bed.
明早还要去上班
We're back at work in the morning.
- 我来了 亲爱的 - 嗨 露西
- I'm coming, sweetie. - Hi, Lucy.
明见 兄弟
See you tomorrow, brother.
我已经复职了 所以今晚别干坏事
Hey, I'm back on the job. So no villainy tonight.
懂了吗
Huh, got it?
我可不保证 爱你哟
I make no promises. Love you!
知道
Uh-huh, right.
我也爱你
I love you too.
好了 爱你们所有 去 去
Alright, every… Go. Go.
去睡觉
Go to bed.
伙计们 走了
Hey. Guys. Come on.
搞什么鬼东西
What the heck is happening?
好像是外面传来的
It's coming from outside!
我们不是说好了吗
Hey, I thought we said no more villainy!
抱歉 兄弟
Sorry, brother.
总得有人继承我们家族的光荣传统
Somebody's got to keep the family tradition alive.
对啊 坏蛋
Yeah! Villain!
坏蛋
Villain!
我们去抓他
Let's get him.
亲爱的 他是我兄弟
Honey, he's my brother.
我们就让他5分钟把
We'll give him a 5 minute head start.